[Music]
oh boy it is a rocking Friday we come on
the air with New York City All Shook Up
after that really surprising and rare
earthquake sending Tremors across the
Northeast the strongest Quake New Jersey
has felt in nearly 250 years we have
stunning video and the after effects
coming up then the new jobs report
coming in hot with historic gains
defying the expectations how will the
fed and voters react to these very
strong numbers plus the NBC News
exclusive on the Moun charges coming for
sham Diddy Colmes and now another member
of his family as well and in tonight's
original more royal family drama with
another new movie about another Infamous
and explosive BBC interview
with a member of the royal family
defending his relationship with Jeffrey
Epstein and are you watching the women's
final four games tonight odds are you'll
have a lot of company and what will
probably be another record-breaking
night for women's college basketball our
team live outside one of the Arenas
where it's all going down coming up
later in the show all right good day I'm
Tom Costello I am in for hlee we come on
the air with concerns about safety after
that shocking and rare earthquake that
rocked parts of the East Coast it is the
strongest Quake that the epicenter New
Jersey has seen in nearly 250 years take
a
look what
happened yeah you'd be bleeping my words
too it was a 4 point8 magnitude
earthquake and centered centered in
Lebanon New Jersey that's about 50 Mi
outside of New York City people reported
feeling the shakes all the way from
Philadelphia up to Boston in one New
Jersey Town more than a dozen people
evacuated from buildings because of
structural damage you can see right
there the buildings are kind of leaning
in right there teams are out as we speak
across the state checking to make sure
the bridges and Roads and buildings and
tunnels are all okay and keep in mind a
lot of them are old right hundreds of
years old as of now no reports of any
injuries now the earthquake triggered
ground stops at two major airports in
the area causing several flights to be
diverted one pilot flying into LaGuardia
warn his passengers take a
listen you're getting updates on your
phone about an earthquake in New York uh
as of now we have not been affected by
that uh weather in LaGuardia is is fine
maybe a little shaky from the ground
shaking I know what you're thinking out
there on the west coast you're thinking
you East Coasters you're all wimps okay
but this isn't California it's so scary
for so many people because the east
coast is not known for this kind of
thing and many buildings really aren't
buil for earthquakes here raising a lot
of concern and questions tonight about
structural safety we have meteorologist
Michelle Gman to break this down for us
but first let's go to my friend rahima
Ellis who's on the ground in Jersey Raha
my daughter lives in New York City I got
an urgent text message from her this
morning rattled she was startled uh this
doesn't happen very often on the East
Coast right what are you hearing from
folks there in
Jersey you're right it does not happen
often and the folks here in New Jersey
they were as you said rattled by all of
this leaving them to wonder what in the
heck is going on I want you to hear from
a woman who's just down the street from
where I'm standing right now she and her
family were at home listen to what they
said about how they felt this earthquake
hitting them
it was absolutely unbelievable how so so
like nothing I've ever felt before I
mean we thought our house coming down to
be honest with you you thought your
house was coming down we thought our
house was coming down I I mean to the
point where everybody was screaming in
this house I mean we just had no idea I
thought that something was exploding
from the basement because the walls were
trembling yeah so she's saying it felt
like something coming up from the ground
that was rattling I was just talking to
another resident about 20 mes from or so
she's here watching us as a matter of
fact Jones said she felt like there was
a plane roaring right over her house
that's how much it was rattling her
leaving her unsettled and concerned
happily she said nothing was broken
there's no structural damage in her
house and essentially that's what we're
hearing from town officials here there
are no reports of any damages any
injuries of any major sort but they're
watching out for all of it Tom you know
the first time I felt one I I fell into
that you know kind of that stereotypical
description I said it felt like a
freight train but that's what it feels
like right and our NBC tan team rather
in in the city there they received two
alerts on their phone but the first one
didn't come for about 30 minutes any
idea why there was such a
delay I don't know but we do have a
sound but I'm going to toss to in just a
moment about that but I was one of those
residents in New York City actually
sitting in my kitchen and watching msnb
C and the kitchen started to move and it
left me feeling very uncomfortable and
it was about 20 minutes later that I got
this alert on my phone listen to what
officials in New York City said about
the concern some people had that those
warnings came 20 to 30 minutes later
take a listen I I think 20 minutes time
to Target is pretty fast for public
notification uh first off there's a lot
of work we have to do to make sure we're
getting confirmation from USGS that this
was actually an earthquake right there's
a lot of things that can cause buildings
to shake two we also need to make sure
we're putting out the proper
[Music]
guidance City officials saying they're
going to have building inspectors
available this weekend for anyone who
might feel some concerns about their
property they'll be able to phone in and
inspectors will be around to respond Tom
yeah so aftershocks is one big question
rahima thank you uh let's bring in
meteorologist Michelle Gman uh and
that's one question mik we see
Aftershock second of all how does this
one compare to the 2011 earthquake that
hit the Northeast including here in DC
right we had significant damage to the
Washington Monument to the National
Cathedral cracks up and down uh the
facades from both both of those
buildings yeah so I was working in
Philly in 2011 that was the first
earthquake that I felt and if you're not
used to that sensation it truly is
something you've never felt before that
sliding it almost feels like the the
Earth is just moving under you not so
much a shaking I felt like a sliding and
that's a coming together so that's the
first thing now that um that that
earthquake was 5.8 on the magnitude
scale so 10 times more powerful that's
how it's sort of rated with earthquakes
and then in terms of the aftershocks
we've had one pretty much every hour
since that 10:00 earthquake so we're
going to continue to feel them the USGS
has told us that we will probably feel
them over the next day or two we have a
4% chance of feeling a 5.0 or greater so
on the lower scale in terms of the
percentage statistically speaking but we
have a 48% chance of feeling a 3.0
magnitude or less so certainly in the
cards the feel more aftershocks as we go
throughout the next couple of hours this
is where the epicenter was it was 3
miles from Lebanon as we just heard from
raema and also uh 3 miles from four
miles from White House station 4.8
magnitude earthquake earthquake which is
notable it's historical a lot of us have
not felt this and we were feeling this
300 miles from the epicenter to the
South to the north all the way to
portions of New England portions to the
South as well this is the third
strongest uh earthquake that we felt in
New Jersey so this is notable we're
going back to the 1700s the 1800s and we
have not felt this for many of us in our
lifetime 5.3 that was in 1783 that was
the strongest and then uh we're going to
continue to watch this Tom because we
certainly could feel those after sh
shocks back to you amazing really no
significant uh damage that we know of or
injuries right so all right Michelle
thank you very much we'll keep watching
and feeling for anything that comes
overseas now in Taiwan where Rescuers
are facing threats of landslides and
Falling Rocks as they tried to save
people trapped out a powerful earthquake
there right off the Island's eastern
coast now we continue to see dramatic
scenes including a rescuer giving an
injured man a piggyback ride out of a
cave after he was stuck there for days
Rescuers have been combing mountainous
areas like these for anyone left behind
in the devastation earlier today crew
found two more bodies in the mountains
that brings now to 12 the number of
people killed in the 7.4 magnitude Quake
more than 1,00 injured 600 plus trapped
at least 13 are missing NBC's Janice
McKie fryer on the ground with more for
us we were inside tooa Gorge national
park today where for days rescue teams
have been working to reach hundreds of
people stranded in the mountains they've
been cut off by landslides helicopters
have been taking supplies to them things
like food and water to tie them over
until they can be airlifted out most of
them have been trapped at a hotel inside
the park where they're said to be safe
but there are still several people who
have been reported missing time is of
the essence that 72-hour window that
rescue officials talk about maximizing
it's now beginning to close rain has
come into the forecast and the main
challenge remains aftershocks there have
been more than 400 of them now and
Counting one rescue team leader told us
every time there is an alert they need
to retreat and for the bigger ones they
simply go back to the station
earthquakes are unavoidable here but
Taiwan has arguably one of the most
advanced systems in the world to deal
with them there are cell phone alerts to
uh let people know what's happening and
as as well as wide public awareness
people just seem to know what to do when
an earthquake Quake strikes there are
also strict building codes and lessons
learned over the years uh that have seen
several buildings reinforced with steel
beam to make them more resistant you'll
see all of the activity at this tilting
building uh behind me for several days
it's been on the verge of collapse
officials have made the quick decision
that they're going to demolish
it Janice thank you very much uh also
interesting those nurses ran to the
babies read that rather than running
away President Biden right now late
today promising more Federal Aid on the
way as part of his tour of the
catastrophic bridge collapse in
Baltimore take a
listen I'm here to say your nation has
your back and I mean it your nation has
your back the President also met
privately with the families of the six
men killed when that massive cargo ship
plowed into the Francis Scott Key bridge
10 days ago crews are still working 247
to clear the tons of Twisted Metal and
concrete from the Waterway losing that
critical bridge is having a massive
impact on travel and on the thousands of
blue collar workers in the very
important Port of Baltimore the Army
Corps of Engineers suggesting it could
fully reopen the port by the end of May
and then there's the global trade
element and angle mbc's George sis is
with the president in Baltimore he joins
us now George uh can you talk more about
the president's conversation with those
families every one of them uh they come
from either Mexico or Central
America hey Toman this is the president
doing what he does the consoler in Chief
coming to these terrible tragedies and
hearing from them they lost their pain
sharing those moments privately with
them he did share a quick anecdote
during his remarks about one of the last
messages that was sent via text by one
of these workers to a girlfriend saying
we just finished pouring the cement we
are waiting for it to dry and then of
course we seen the video and we know
what happens next I also Tom want to
direct your attention to what's
happening here on the ground in the
Baltimore area behind me is a memorial
it is a vigil that has been growing
since the collapse a large vigil plann
for this weekend here people from the
community family members friends
stopping by to pay their respects to the
men who lost their lives those six lives
lost those four that are still
unaccounted for and very briefly Tom I
want to tell you that earlier today I
had a brief conversation with Julio
cantes one of the survivors of the
bridge he was actually in bed at home
when I first approached the home his
wife telling me he had a chest injury he
answered the door today seeming in much
better spirits he didn't want to go on
camera and say anymore saying they're
still looking for some privacy as
they're still mourning the loss of two
of their family members but it just
tells you sort of the evolution and sort
of the idea that the cameras may have
left but the pain is still all too real
for those family members so again the
president taking that time today to not
only tour the wreckage and really see
firsthand those harrowing images of the
bridge no longer being there but also
talking with those family members and
sharing their grief with them and he
something he also addressed in his
remarks that he understands the pain of
loss as well Tom he does indeed and he's
talked about that and it often helps
families George thank you very much
George ciss in Baltimore for us uh the
Israeli military has now dismissed two
senior officers and is releasing a new
report on what it calls serious errors
and violations that led to the deadly
Israeli attack which killed seven Aid
workers in Gaza meanwhile the world
kitchen world Central Kitchen is now
demanding an independent probe into
those strikes which prime minister
Benjamin Netanyahu calls unintentional
here in Washington the Biden
Administration offering cautious
optimism over Israel's new steps that
would allow more Aid to flow into Gaza
just 24 hours after the president gave
Netanyahu an ultimatum to do more to
protect civilians in Gaza or risk losing
American Support NBC's Hala garani is on
the ground in Jerusalem Hala walk us
through the latest on the Israeli
militaries Mula here and the removal of
these officers is this significant or
are these officers just kind of taking
the
fall so you mentioned there that uh two
officers were were fired and that some
military commanders were reprimanded
it's important to underline though that
it doesn't appear as though any charges
will be brought against them for what
the Israeli military itself has called a
grave error it is it said that there was
a case of mistaken identity that led to
the uh not one not two but three strikes
against that world Central Kitchen
Convoy uh and uh therefore it doesn't
appear as though Beyond this reprimand
of the senior commanders and this
dismissal of two middle ranking officers
uh at least uh at this stage there will
be any consequences uh for what the
Israeli military uh has acknowledged was
uh a mistake and a case of mistake in
identity that essentially is a tragedy
for the people on the ground but what
charitable organizations will uh
underline in this case is that this is
not an isolated event the Secretary
General of the United Nations for
example has said that almost 200 Aid
workers have been killed since October
7th and so therefore that this is a
wider problem that goes beyond the
tragedy uh that left seven World Central
uh kitchen workers dead and that a a a
wider issue has to be addressed about
how the Israeli military is conducting
this operation that has led to these
deaths and to the deaths of tens of
thousands of Palestinians including uh
pretty much all of the infrastructure of
the strip at least in the northern part
of the uh of Gaza Tom Hala has President
Biden's ultimatum to Netanyahu has that
resonated with the Israeli government do
they take him seriously or do they plan
to just proceed with as
usual well the Prime Minister Benjamin
Netanyahu has done something he's
resisted uh so far which is to open the
Ares Crossing this is quite significant
it's in the northern part of the Gaza
Strip it's been closed since October 7th
but the Secretary of State Anthony
blinkin like many others is essentially
saying you know we have to wait and see
if the Israeli government follows
through on these promises here's what he
said in Brussels today
it's very important that Israel is
taking full responsibility for this
incident it's also important that it
appears to be taking steps to hold those
responsible uh accountable as Israel
pursues any military operations against
Hamas it has to prioritize the
protection of civilians it has to make
that job number
one so we don't know exactly when these
Aid deliveries might take place uh via
the AES Crossing there have been some
reports that perhaps they could start on
Sunday but we're still waiting uh for
more information on that front Tom all
right halani who's on the scene for us
there in his gril thank you Hala to Wall
Street we go now where the stock markets
closed this Friday in the green after a
March jobs report with a lot of
superlatives experts are calling it
stronger than expected booming eye
popping here's a Chuck of the boards the
Dow closed 300 points higher on this
Friday rebound but at the same time it
registered its worst week this year so
far the S&P and the NASDAQ both up more
than 1% on the day as well now listen to
this esorts predicted the economy would
add about 200,000 jobs in March instead
it was a stunner a blowout 303,000 jobs
were added 50% more than what the
economists had expected it is the 39th
straight month listen to that 39th
straight month of job growth in this
country no doubt it's a very good sign
that the economy is on the right PA path
and painting a very different picture
from a year ago remember that the
consensus there was that a recession was
imminent mbc's Christine Romans is
breaking all the data down for us so
Christine good news good news right more
people have jobs wages are up but good
news can also be bad news if it means
the economy is still hot which keeps
prices high and therefore the FED may
not be in any rush to cut interest rates
well I mean look Tom do you cut interest
rates with a job market looks like this
I mean you cut interest rates to Goose
in economy right you cut interest rates
when it needs a little bit of help uh
that does not look like it needs a
little bit of help here I mean look at
the job market just this year has
actually accelerated and the
unemployment rate you talked about all
those superlatives a soup of
superlatives here's one 40 or 28 months
below 4% for the jobless rate that
hasn't happened since the 1960s another
period of a very very strong job market
so look I think six months ago the
feeling was or even three months ago the
feeling was there'd be three rate cuts
by the Fed
this year um to try to take some of that
tightening off the table from all those
rate uh rate hikes but what I see here
is a job market that has absorbed all of
those rate hikes and is still strong uh
and and wages 4.1% you're so right to
bring up wages 4.1% a little bit cooler
than the month before so maybe that
gives some comfort to the FED that it
can just wait it doesn't have to be
cutting interest rates here anytime soon
you still have wages Rising faster than
your bills and that's something that's
that's really really important here yeah
but as you know uh you know that's not
keeping up with inflation in the grocery
store right so your wages are up 4% or
so but year-over-year or over two years
your grocery items are up like 30% or
something like that yeah so you're
absolutely right it's only recently that
that wages have been steadily increasing
and inflation has been tapering off but
there's three years of inflation scars
as I call them uh in the economy so that
may take time it honestly might take
time but we are starting to see it as
some of these in some of these uh polls
from people like this week I last week
you know the University of Michigan poll
showed that people 55 and older are
starting to feel a lot better about the
economy now if you're 55 and older what
do you probably have more exposure to a
record high stock market and record high
home prices right people who are younger
they are still dealing with a lot of
costs and troubles in the economy one of
the reasons I think why the B
Administration is still going forward so
aggressively with student loan
forgiveness where they can trying to
alleviate some of the pay pain there for
those younger people very good point
absolutely Christine thank you very much
appreciate the expertise uh the clock is
ticking to get your eclipse glasses and
make your Monday afternoon plans because
as you probably already know have you
heard about it a total solar eclipse is
coming to America it's a Once in a
generation maybe a once in a lifetime
event when the moon fully blocks the
Sun's light and that creates complete
darkness for just a few minutes the path
of totality you see there run through
more than a dozen states turning them
into huge tourist attractions let's
bring in NBC's Priscilla Thompson who's
in one of those areas just out of Dallas
uh Priscilla Dallas is one of the first
cities that will be in the zone as it
were when this Eclipse starts in Mexico
right and I hear tourists are flooding
in
already yeah Tom there are 83 counties
here in Texas that are going to be in
that path of totality and tourists are
already starting to make their way in
there's going to be huge watch parties
and uh we have seen that hotels and
rentals along this path of totality are
almost entirely booked including here at
the hotel Vin in Grapevine Texas they
are doing a lot of specialty uh Foods on
the menus and of course specialty drinks
we've got Patty and Daniel here so
really quickly just tick through for me
what are these all right so we got the
day and night drink basically a chilon
with a black salt Rim also got a rum mu
we're going to call that dark and stormy
got the ring of fire with vodka in
jalapeno vodka infused and then we also
got the My Thai uh this is our totality
ma Thai a traditional ma Thai uh White
Rum orot uh Orange CA lime juice and
floated with the dark rum and it gets a
little something special there thank you
and so that is a taste of what tourists
are going to be coming in looking to uh
get we also spoke to the manager here
about how they're preparing for this
influx of visitors and I want to play
some of what he shared
we got International and domestic people
are coming in calling even till today uh
just to get the reservation in so it is
busy right we wanted to make sure what
can we possibly do to curate an
experience for each one of them that's
coming in this whole weekend leading up
to
Monday and Tom guests here coming in for
the eclipse will also have an
opportunity to take something back with
them the hotel has done these special
bourbon bottles of bourbon they have
spent three years working on that so
folks will be able to take that souvenir
back but it gives you a sense of just
how long businesses here have been
preparing for this incredible moment and
this incredible influx of visitors to
towns like this one Tom I I think to do
a thorough job you ought to test out
these uh tourist attractions I I would
just say off camera but you know I
should right yeah well off CA after my
last live shot I'll get a little sip Hey
listen really quickly some people are
actually superstitious about a total
eclipse right
yeah um yes that is a thing and it's
important to note that during an eclipse
some things might get a little strange
animals might start acting a little
weird thinking that it's night time
preparing to go to sleep but I will tell
you the thing that people here in Texas
who are coming in to visit are bugging
out about is the weather it was supposed
to have some of the best weather viewing
uh best viewing but now we're looking at
cloudy weather and potentially uh some
storms here so folks really hoping that
that will hold off for those 4 minutes
in that 1:00 hour on Monday so that they
can see it in all its Glory before that
rolls in Tom all right they can watch
you right here on NBC news now as well
Priscilla thank you very much we'll
check with you uh throughout the coming
days after the break from us we'll show
you some of the new documentary about
prince Andrew and the interview about
Jeffrey Epstein that ended his Royal
life and Tide Pods getting recalled
because of dangers to Children you're
going to want to see this we're back
stay with us
[Music]
all right let's get you over now to the
five things our team thinks you should
know about tonight number one a medical
examiner is correcting the initial
autopsy report for the pilot in that
fatal Arizona hot air balloon crash the
original reports said the pilot had
ketamine in his system and the drug was
not used in resuscitation efforts after
the crash but now County authorities say
Medics did in fact give him ketamine
while transporting him to the the
hospital for resuscitation efforts
you'll recall four people died after the
balloon fell roughly 2,000 ft back in
January number two the TSA tells the
Washington Post that hundreds of people
have bypassed airport security measures
in the past 12 months they're doing
things like sneaking through ID
checkpoints and going the wrong
direction through one-way exit Lanes the
TSA spokesperson says most of these were
really bypasses that are rather rare or
inadvertent and unintentional actions by
passengers number three Proctor and
Gamble recalling more than 8 million
defective bags of laundry detergent pods
the company says there is a packaging
flaw that could hurt children the
effective products include Tide Pods
Gain Flings Ace pods and aerial pods
made between September of last year to
February of this year PNG says there's
been three reports of children ingesting
contents of the laundry packets no
report reports of injuries number four
99 Cents Only stores are shutting down
all 371 locations the CSO make that the
CEO says it's because of factors like
the pandemic and shifting consumer
demand and that it was quote very
extremely difficult to make that
decision the chain will liquidate all of
its merchandise number five USC freshman
bronny James LeBron james' son will
enter the 2024 NBA draft as well as the
the college transfer portal now remember
over the summer bronnie suffered Cardiac
Arrest while at a basketball workout and
had to have a heart procedure that
sidelined him for several months and
just a bit from us our NBC News digital
documentary showing a mother's fight to
save her son held hostage by Hamas and a
decades long case of stolen identity is
giving shades of Don Draper we're coming
back
[Music]
bottom of the hour and NBC News covers
hundreds of stories every day it is
awfully tough to read watch or listen to
everything so our Bureau teams have
identified some highlights here's what
they say is going on down in their
regions we call the segment the local
all right from our Midwest Bureau a
Wisconsin man has pleaded guilty to
using a fake identity listen to this for
more than 30 years according to a plea
deal the man used the victim's identity
in every aspect of his life it was so
convincing the actual victim was falsely
imprisoned for identity theft and ended
up in a psychiatric hospital when a
judge said he couldn't stand trial
police figured it all out when they
tested both men's DNA out of our
Southern Bureau Police in Texas arrested
a mother and daughter for allegedly
performing sorry Mom performing illegal
butt injections across the US without a
medical license you're not supposed to
do that now according to a court dock
the women tried to perform the service
on a customer who was actually an
undercover officer not a good move
they're said to appear in court next
week and from our Northeast Bureau six
inmates at one New York State Prison
will get to watch Monday's solar eclipse
now remember they sued over the state's
decision to lock down prisons during the
eclipse for safety reasons they argued
it violated their constitutional rights
the prison says it's looking into other
Rel religious requests to view the
eclipse now to new reporting from NBC
News digital docs our team has been
talking about and talking to one
mother's fight to bring her son back
home after he was taken hostage by Hamas
back on October 7th this is 23-year-old
HS Goldberg Poland in the nearly six
months since her sum was taken Rachel
Goldberg Poland has become a vocal
advocate in the effort to free the more
than 100 hostages still being held by
Hamas all while trying to pretend
everything is
normal today is day 27 her's still not
home 52 75 86 today is day 100 since my
son was stolen from me it's sad to be
known for something really painful and
really scary and that's what people
think of when they see
me every time we spoke to anyone in the
media they would say how many days has
it been so I just took masking tape and
started to make these
numbers and it makes people really ask
how are we allowing this to continue to
[Music]
happen the hostage families have to
pretend to be normal if we want to
function and if we want to save
[Music]
them the first thing in the morning I
always say to myself and now pretend to
human and I get out of bed and I put on
this costume of being a person I have a
walk that I do now in the mornings that
I've
crafted so that I don't see anybody and
I walk with my head down and I always
wear sunglasses I often have a hood if I
see people in the distance I cross to
the other side of the
street and all day long
it's kind of like someone's holding a
branding iron on your back and you can't
let anybody
[Music]
know I was asked early on if I would
speak at the United Nations in New York
and so I did why is no one crying out
for these people to be allowed access to
the Red Cross why is no one demanding
just proof of life we felt that the
advocacy for the hostage situation was
so important that we really never wanted
to say
[Applause]
[Music]
no I've had
episodes where I do break it's better
when I know that it's coming and I can
you know say I'll be right back and you
know go to my room or go to the bathroom
or go somewhere where it's not so
public but that's not the way trauma
works
so there are definitely times where I'm
out there screaming or crying or laying
on the
street I'm also
extremely
heartbroken over the unbelievable
suffering of hundreds of thousands of
innocent gauen people what they are
going through it's unbearable and so
painful to
watch right now there are hundreds of
thousands of people suffering in this on
both sides and it's time for the
suffering to
[Music]
stop on Shabbat morning I sit
down cross-legged right in front of this
big poster that we have of him that is
behind our front door I look into his
eyes and I talk to him and I tell him
you have to stay strong mentally
spiritually psychologically physically
religiously you have to survive you have
no choice we are coming you can make it
through this and you're going to have a
long beautiful life
one mother we'll be right
back back now to an NBC News exclusive
with the son of recording artist Shan
ddy Colmes also now accused of sexual
assault the new lawsuit first obtained
by NBC News accuses 26-year-old
Christian Colmes of sexually assaulting
a woman in December of 22 she says she
thought she was being hired for a
wholesome family Excursion on a yacht
that Diddy charted instead she found a
quote hedonistic environment Diddy is
named in the lawsuit as well accused of
aiding and abetting his son in the last
couple of hours we've heard from a
lawyer for Diddy and his son calling
this a lewd and meritless claim from the
accuser's lawyer saying father and son
will file a motion to dismiss the
lawsuit now remember this moment from
those dramatic police raids earlier this
month at Diddy's home in Los Angeles and
also Miami Diddy has denied all
allegations related to the wave of
sexual assault and sex trafficking
allegations that he faces Chloe Mass
joins me now Chloe what else can you
tell us about this lawsuit against
Christian and Diddy Colmes and did this
come as a surprise nice to see you I
mean this woman is accusing Christian
Colmes of an incident that allegedly
took place in December 2022 just days
before Diddy had a really big party on
this yacht uh for New Year's Eve and the
victim claims that she was drugged and
sexually assaulted by Christian Colmes
again Christian coles's lawyer denying
these allegations uh she claims that
there are also audio recordings that
were taken by a music producer um who
was on The Yacht who was always
recording uh things that were going on
and just happened to catch some of the
exchanges between Christian Colmes and
this alleged victim that they believe
backs up her claims um NBC News has not
been able to to independ independently
verify that and in the lawsuit there are
also uh photos of alleged bruises that
she says uh are are because Christian
Colmes grabbed her now all of this um
you know was taking place allegedly in
December of
2022 and she claims that she was in a
room and somebody came in saw that this
was a bad situation and that that kept
her from being assaulted further and she
was able to get out and now she is
seeking unspecified Financial damages um
and again we've seen that uh you know
sha Diddy Colmes and his son are both
saying that they are going to fight this
and Diddy is included in all of this
because he was the one that procured the
yacht yeah so walk us through again the
allegations against Diddy and where the
investigation stands right now so I want
to just go through this timeline that we
have so this all kicked off in November
of 2023 when uh one of uh Diddy's
ex-girlfriends Cassie uh but her name is
Cassandra Ventura well-known singer and
two others sued Diddy for sexual abuse
something that he denied now uh you know
sha Diddy Colmes he settled that lawsuit
with Cassie like just about a day or so
later for an undisclosed amount of money
then December a woman comes forward uh
you we don't know her identity but
claims that she was raped by Diddy when
she was 17 years old um and then another
lawsuit February 2024 from a former
record producer who worked with Diddy on
his love album um accusing him of all
sorts of things including assault and
then like you showed that footage that
unbelievable footage of Diddy's homes
multiple properties being raided by
federal authorities last week and he
Diddy has not been charged with anything
criminally we do not know what those
Federal investigators found and if
they're ever going to reveal if anything
was found um and then obviously this
lawsuit that NBC News has exclusively
obtained and so you know things are not
looking good and um it'll be interesting
to see happens over the course of the
coming weeks okay Chloe Moss breaking
the news thank you very much Chloe
coming up from Moss ticket prices for
tonight's women's final four through the
roof the ncaa's President says there is
no peak to the sports success what about
ticket prices we're coming
[Music]
back okay so we are just hours away now
from the most anticipated women's Final
Four ever with four huge storylines
about to play out in Cleveland tonight
there's the bracket the opening game
with South Carolina the huge favorites
against an upstart North Carolina State
then the night cap a a heavyweight bout
with yukon's Paige Beckers and the
Superstar of this sport right now you
know who she is Iowa's Caitlyn Clark
audience experts expect more than more
records I should say after 12 million
people tuned in for Mondays LSU Iowa
game with the athletic predicting
anywhere from 8 million viewers to
nearly 17 million for the final if it's
Iowa against South Carolina NBC Sam
Brock will explain how all of this turns
into dollars for the athletes in just a
moment but let's start though with NBC's
Jesse kers who's in Cleveland uh just
outside the site of this year's women's
final four but you got a rough
assignment buddy you get you get to
watch the final four but this is not
just I I have a press pass that I think
would be a pretty penny but of course
ethics preclude me from uh indulging in
that we're going to go in there in a
little bit and check out these games uh
you just set the stage we're looking at
some Powerhouse matchups and and the the
finale to what has been a historic
tournament for the women's game the NCAA
says that each of the rounds in this
Championship leading up to this weekend
have broken attendance records and you
just talked about Monday night LSU Iowa
it was a rematch from the the uh the
championship game last year and there
were more people watching that game than
the championship last year just gives
you an idea of the energy around these
games and like I just mentioned it's not
cheap to get in here take a look at some
of these ticket prices according to
tickp this is the highest we've ever
seen for an average ticket price for the
women's final four and the prices are
almost double what they were last year
just gives you an idea of how much
excitement there is around this we
caught up with some NCAA officials
earlier including the vice president for
women's basketball here's part of what
she shared with us
let go I think it's a combination of
both uh you know exposure through TV but
it's social media our players out there
their personalities are coming out um we
have great coaches that are faces of the
game as well the skill and athleticism
on the court is phenomenal these are
great players the basketball skill the
the power that they
have we're looking at a lot of star
power across this game but of course one
name continues to stick out Tom and
that's Kaylor par yeah Jesse I've got
offers already coming in right now for
your press pass texting me right now all
right buddy uh listen we should know the
women are playing in a typical 18,000
seat basketball arena right we're not
even talking about the men's final four
playing in a 70,000 football stadium so
any talk about when we might approach
parody yeah so we we talked to the NCAA
about this earlier in remember time it's
just a couple years ago that there was a
lot of attention on a disparity between
the weight room facilities for example
at the 2021 tournament for the women
versus the men and the NCAA President
and Vice President we spoke with earlier
talking about investment they've made to
bring that parody to both the men's and
the women's tournament and they said
that even with tournaments planned out
ahead specifically San Antonio they're
looking at larger venues for the women
and of course they plan these things out
years in advance uh but the expectation
is that this game continues to grow for
the women here's part of what the
president of the NCAA shared with us
earlier
I want to think about this as something
where there is no peak right it's just
going to keep going up and the goal for
all of us is to continue to make the
Investments to drive that but at the
same time to be able to make the changes
despite the fact that we have to plan
many years in advance to be able to
absorb and um and take advantage of
that and that's of course what we're
talking about in iners attendance
specifically but don't forget Tom as you
mentioned talking about more than 12
million people that tune in on Monday
night for a quarterfinal ESPN says that
was the most watched women's college
basketball game
[Music]
ever and we come on the air at this hour
with breaking news we are just now
learning about a body being found
unidentified at the Baltimore bridge
collapse we will bring you the latest on
the ground about that story New York
City All Shook Up at after that really
surprising and rare earthquake sent
Tremors all across the Northeast the
strongest Quake New Jersey has felt in
250 years the stunning video and the
after effects then the new jobs report
came in very hot historic gains Define
the expectations whatever happened to a
recession and how will the FED now react
what about voters reacting to these
strong numbers plus our digital doc Team
new heroin reporting on one mom's fight
to bring her son a hostage held in Gaza
to bring him back home that is later in
the show plus the NBC News exclusive on
the mounting charges coming now for sha
ddy Colmes and another member of his
family his son and then there's the
eclipse you've heard about it the
countdown is on we've got the latest on
the preparations for this once in a
generation event coming up in just a
couple of days hey there I'm Tom
Costello happy Friday I am in for H and
tonight we are just learning in the last
few minutes that a body has been found
at the site of the tragic Baltimore
bridge collapse that according to the
family of the deceased and it comes as
President Biden makes a key trip to
Baltimore to tour the wreckage today he
met privately with the families of the
six men killed when that massive cargo
ship plowed into the Francis Scott Key
bridge 10 days ago and the president
late today promising more federal aid is
on the way for the city here's where he
said I'm here to say your nation has
your back and I mean it your nation has
your
back so Salvage and Recovery teams are
still working 247 to clear the tons of
Twisted Metal and concrete from the
Waterway let's bring in NBC's George
sois who's on the ground George uh you
have some details right about one of the
victims a body has now been
discovered yeah that's right Tom the
brother of Maynard Sandoval swazo
telling me moments ago that the family
was called in today saying that they did
get confirmation that mayor's body was
found there at the wreckage of the
bridge are saying that they have to get
more details tomorrow after the body is
process but this was sort of the update
that they were fearing the most uh they
were expecting it but obviously it's
news that really resonates and hits
heavily for this family as they were
awaiting word if their loved one would
ever be found some other details slow to
come in at this moment but again the
brother who I spoke with last week
during the bridge collapse telling me he
does leave behind a young family as well
and they were really praying that his
body would be found relatively soon
after this collapse but they were among
those other family groups those four
family members that were still waiting
for any update and again telling me that
this morning they were given a call to
report to an office an undisclosed
location and now confirming to me that
they did find his body and now again
they are waiting for that body to be
processed uh and we are waiting more
details about maybe where the body
exactly was located as we learned uh
during the initial recovery of two of
the bodies last week some of those men
were in vehicles not clear at this point
if mayar's body was in a vehicle at this
time again some of the details I'm
working through with the family at this
moment but again just a tragic update to
an already tragic story and it comes as
you mentioned the president was here
today meeting with those family members
and earlier today I actually met with
one of the survivors of the bridge
collapse Julio Cervantes who was
bedridden for a time after the collapse
after suffering a chest wound today
answering the door still not commenting
because they are still reeling over the
loss of two of their family members but
he appearing to be at least in much
better spirits and health after
surviving that fall but again just a
tragic update for the swazo family who
again telling us telling NBC Today that
the body of their loved one was
recovered Tom well I know his family in
Honduras last week was U was hoping that
he would be discover and brought back to
Honduras so there's some Solace there
George thank you very much George soise
all right breaking right now after
shocks being felt across the Northeast
after that wild and rare earthquake that
shook the area this morning it is the
strongest Quake that the epicenter in
New Jersey has seen in nearly 250 years
take a look at this
[Music]
yeah they're not used to earthquakes up
in the Northeast it was a 4.8 magnitude
Quake centered just outside of Lebanon
New Jersey just 50 miles or so outside
of New York City people reported feeling
the shakes all the way from Philly up to
Boston in one New Jersey Town more than
a dozen people were evacuated from
buildings because of structural damage
now take a look right there you see
those houses kind of leaning together
that's what they're concerned about
teams are out as we speak across the
states checking to make sure that that
Bridges and Roads and buildings and
tunnels that they're all okay as of
right now no reports of any injuries the
earthquake triggered ground stops at two
major airports in the area causing
several flights to be diverted Newark
and JFK now remember this isn't
California it's scary for a lot of
people in the East the East Coast not
known for this kind of thing many
buildings aren't built for earthquakes
they're quite old and that's raising a
lot of concern about structural safety
we have meteorologist Michelle grman to
break this down for us first though
let's go to Emily aeta who's on the
ground there in New Jersey Emily you
just felt an Aftershock where you are
right
now yeah that's right Tom literally a
matter of minutes ago and this is
something that officials have been
urging people to watch for in the coming
days these continued aftershocks we know
there have been more than six at this
point and it happened to it almost felt
like a vibration of the ground there's
this moment where all of our crew here
we were looking around at each other
like did you just feel that did you just
feel that people start coming outside
asking did you just feel that so this is
a continued threat that people want that
officials want people to keep an eye on
though to a more minor degree compared
to the 4.8 magnitude earthquake that
really rocked this town in particular
and hearing from people there was a lot
of confusion trying to make sense of
what could that have been some people
thought their houses were collapsing or
there was some kind of explosion because
as you mentioned this is not something
nor easterners are familiar with now
what's happening right now there are
teams across the region from here even
300 miles out that are going around to
different buildings Bridges
infrastructure checking to see on the
Integrity of those things that will
continue to happen in the coming days
here's what one woman told me about her
terrifying
experience the whole entire house was
shaking I mean pretty pretty
aggressively the walls were trembling
and I what instantly went through my
mind was that I thought there was an
explosion happening from the basement
and this is the strongest earthquake to
hit the East Coast since 2011 and it is
the strongest earthquake to hit New
Jersey in nearly 250 Years Tom well
we've also had an online frenzy as you
would expect the Empire State Building
account its Twitter account x uh playing
it into saying I am fine then just
moments ago saying not again with the
Aftershock uh listen this is serious but
it's also taking off in true meme
culture fashion as well right
yeah absolutely true meme fashion
culture that's that's for sure and
you're seeing so much chatter on social
media I think because there are no
reported injuries and there's no
widespread significant damage that
people are having a little bit more fun
with it on social media I've seen posts
about t-shirts already coming out saying
I have survived the New York City
earthquake some joking that this
earthquake merely knocked over a single
chair maybe some people wondering how
Californians would be laughing at us in
this moment right now but I think as you
pointed out that for so many people in
the Northeast unfamiliar with these
kinds of situations it was in the moment
really scary and confusing as the ground
rocked for seconds Tom yeah and let's
keep in mind this is also an area that
was hit on 911 so all of that's still
very real for people uh in the New York
area Emily thank you very much all right
let's go now to meteorologist Michelle
grman Michelle we we just talked about
how this is taking off online with the
jokes but when you hear from people on
the ground they really felt this and
they were they were really terrified so
why is it that that this doesn't quite
stack up to the magnitudes of the Quakes
out there in California and all those
folks in California right now are just
shaking their heads at us here in the
Northeast yeah we can almost hear it
right uh well we can tell them a few
things because we are feeling it
different than they would in California
there's three major reasons and I know
Tom you're a science nerd like I am and
you really love this stuff but this is
really interesting one of the major
reasons is we have really dense rock as
compared to the West we have the
appalachin mountains which are way older
than the Sierra Nevada mountains way
older than the Rockies so they've been
uh exposed to pressure and temperatures
and just kind of packed in so it those
rocks and the crust is a Little Bit
Stronger easily transmits this energy so
we feel it stronger and it transmits it
even wider than it would in California
so you can look at some maps um online
where you see maybe an epicenter in
California and the uh length isn't as as
wide but look at this in the Northeast
you can see how far it goes and it can
go 300 miles where we're feeling it
that's the first reason the second
reason was this was really shallow so
when you have a shallow earthquake you
feel it sooner and you feel it more
because there's not a lot of space for
that energy to go it's going to go right
to the surface and then the third reason
are the buildings right so in California
I was talking to chase Kane who is a
climate specialist for our local MBC
stations and he said he's been through
so many in California but those
buildings are made under a strict code
where they tend to sway with the
earthquake here we don't have that so we
feel it more you know I heard some
people where they felt their building
shaking they never felt this before and
keep this in mind Tom we felt it in 2011
we felt an earthquake in the 80s as well
but many people haven't and they might
not again because this is the third
strongest earthquake in New Jersey back
to the 1700s the 1800s you have to go
back so they may never feel this again
and then let's touch upon what Emily
said because I think this is super super
important we do have many chances for
aftershocks uh that's from the USGS so
what you want to do is drop cover and
hold if you do feel this now
statistically speaking we're not going
to see a stronger one but we could but
statistically that's 4% but we do have a
48% chance of seeing a three magnitude
or less back to you you know you just
made a great point because New York City
is built on unbelievably strong Bedrock
right I've been in the tunnels
Underground when they dug out a new
Subway and so when it's that hard of
course if if you start rattling and
shaking it it's going to really spread
uh through the region as opposed to
something that's a little softer mhm
yeah that's exactly right yeah
interesting stuff Michelle see we geek
out on nerdy stuff thanks very much on a
Friday that's right all right thank you
very much all right overseas now Taiwan
Rescuers there facing threats of
landslides and Falling Rocks as they try
to say people trapped after an
earthquake there off the Island's
eastern coast we continue to see
dramatic scenes including this round
rescuer giving an injured man a
piggyback ride out of a cave after he
was stuck there for days Rescuers have
been caling mountainous areas like these
for anybody left behind in the
devastation earlier today Cruz found two
more bodies in the mountains that brings
now to 12 the number of people killed in
that 7.4 magnitude quake in Taiwan more
than 1100 people injured 600 trapped and
at least 13 missing NBC's Janice Mackie
fryer is on the ground in Taiwan
we were inside tooa Gorge national park
today where for days rescue teams have
been working to reach hundreds of people
stranded in the mountains they've been
cut off by landslides helicopters have
been taking supplies to them things like
food and water to tie them over until
they can be airlifted out most of them
have been trapped at a hotel inside the
park where they're said to be safe but
there are still several people who have
been reported missing
time is of the essence that 72-hour
window that rescue officials talk about
maximizing it's now beginning to close
rain has come into the forecast and the
main challenge remains aftershocks there
have been more than 400 of them now and
Counting one rescue team leader told us
every time there is an alert they need
to retreat and for the bigger ones they
simply go back to the station
earthquakes are unavoidable here but
Taiwan has arguably one of the most
advanced systems in the world to deal
with them there are cell phone alerts to
uh let people know what's happening and
as as well as wide public awareness
people just seem to know what to do when
an earthquake strikes there are also
strict building codes and lessons
learned over the years uh that has seen
several buildings reinforced with steel
beam to make them more resistant you'll
see all of the activity at this tilting
building uh behind me for several days
it's been on the verge of collapse
officials have made the quick decision
that they're going to demolish
it Janice mcky frer on the ground in
Taiwan for us other news the Israeli
military has now dismissed two senior
officers and is releasing a new report
on what it calls quote serious errors
and violations that led to the deadly
Israeli attack which killed seven Aid
workers in Gaza meanwhile the world's
Central Kitchen is now demanding an
independent probe into those strikes
prime minister Benjamin Netanyahu calls
them unintentional while here in
Washington the Biden Administration is
offering cautious optimism their words
over Israel's new steps to allow more
Aid into Gaza just 24 hours after
President Biden gave Netanyahu an
ultimatum to do more to protect
civilians in Gaza or risk losing
American Support NBC's holla gani is on
the ground in Jerusalem uh holla can you
give us more information what more do we
know about how the world Central Kitchen
is responding to this this report and
just the devastating loss of these seven
individuals well you mentioned the world
Central Kitchen demanding an independent
a fully independent probe into this
attack that left seven of its employees
its workers dead we heard from the IDF
spokesperson Daniel hagari who added a
little bit to the written statement that
was put out today taking full
responsibility for the attack calling it
as you mentioned there uh that serious
errors were committed Daniel hagari
saying it was a terrible chain of errors
and should not have happened and that
the Israeli military is fully
responsible but for the world Central
Kitchen for other Aid organizations this
speaks to a wider problem these seven
people who died on April 1st are not the
only humanitarians who've lost their
lives since October 7th as the UN
Secretary General mentioned today almost
200 humanitarians have been killed in
strikes and in the violence since
October 7th uh and this is an addition
of course to the tremendous loss of
civilian life so the eight organizations
are saying that now more needs to be
done not just to protect humanitarian
workers but to get that desperately
needed Aid into the Gaza Strip in a much
more seamless fashion and that the
Israeli government has to do more to
facilitate that Tom and holla give us an
update on the aid that is supposed to be
flowing into Gaza with famine striking
much of that region and the death toll
is surpassing 30,000 how long could that
Aid actually
last right so we're not sure exactly
when uh what the Israeli uh government
has promised will happen will
materialize that the eras Crossing in
the north is meant to reopen it's been
closed since October 7th that the ashdod
port is meant to be used these are
according to to the statements from the
Israeli government over the last 24
hours following that what was described
as a tense phone call between President
Biden and Benjamin Netanyahu the Israeli
Prime Minister but um look in the past
the Israeli government has promised
you'll remember a few weeks ago to flood
the north with Aid that didn't happen
the Secretary of State Anthony blinkin
is also saying that umu you know we need
to see on the ground exactly what trans
spires before making a judgment as to
whether or not the Israeli government
has fulfilled its promise listen he was
in Brussels
today it's very important that Israel is
taking full responsibility for this
incident it's also important that it
appears to be taking steps to hold those
responsible uh accountable as Israel
pursues any military operations against
Hamas it has to prioritize the
protection of civilians it has to make
that job number
one so again we waiting to see when and
uh Aid will go through and how many
trucks how many vehicles will be allowed
in uh that's something we're going to be
keeping a close uh close eye on Tom
holla we really benefit from your
expertise and your intimate knowledge uh
of the situation on the ground thank you
very much halani to Wall Street we go
right now where the stock market's
closed this Friday in the green after a
March jobs report with a lot of
superlatives experts are saying it was
stronger than expected it was booming it
was High popping yeah that's all true so
here's a check of the boards the Dow up
300 points on a Friday a rebound there
but at the same time the Dow also had
its worst week in 2024 the S&P in the
NASDAQ up more than 1% today experts
have predicted the economy would add
200,000 new jobs in March instead the
stunner 303,000 jobs added 50% more than
what economists had expected it is the
39th straight month of job growth in
America America no doubt it's a very
good sign that the economy is on the
right path painting a very different
picture from a year ago remember we were
talking then about a recession being
imminent NBC's Christine Romans is of
course breaking it all down for
us Christine good news good news right
more people have jobs wages are up but
good news can also be bad news if it
means the economy is still hot which
keep prices high and therefore the FED
may not be in any rush to cut interest
rates
well I mean look Tom do you cut interest
rates with the job market looks like
this I mean you cut interest rates to
Goose an economy right you cut interest
rates when it needs a little bit of help
uh that does not look like it needs a
little bit of help here I mean look at
the job market just this year has
actually accelerated and the
unemployment rate you talked about all
those superlatives a soup of
superlatives here's one 40 or 28 months
below 4% for the jobl rate that hasn't
happened since the 1960s another period
of a very very strong job market so look
I think months ago the feeling was or
even three months ago the feeling was
there'd be three rate cuts by the fed
this year um to try to take some of that
tightening off the table from all those
rate uh rate hikes but what I see here
is a job market that has absorbed all of
those rate hikes and is still strong uh
and and wages 4.1% you're so right to
bring up wages 4.1% a little bit cooler
than the month before so maybe that
gives some comfort to the FED that it
can just wait it doesn't have to be
cutting interest rates here anytime soon
you still have wages Rising faster than
your bills and that's something that's
that's really really important here yeah
but as you know uh you know that's not
keeping up with inflation in the grocery
store right so your wages are up 4% or
so but year-over-year or over two years
your grocery items are up like 30% or
something like that yeah so you're
absolutely right it's only recently that
the wages have been steadily increasing
and inflation has been tapering off but
there's three years of inflation scars
as I call them uh in the economy so that
may take time it honestly might take
time but we are starting to see it in
some of these in some of these uh polls
from people like this week I last week
you know the University of Michigan poll
showed that people 55 and older are
starting to feel a lot better about the
economy now if you're 55 and older what
do you probably have more exposure to a
record high stock market and record high
home prices right people who are younger
they are still dealing with a lot of
costs and troubles in the economy one of
the reasons I think why the Biden
Administration is still going forward so
aggressively with student loan
forgiveness where they can trying to
alleviate some of the pain there for
those younger people very good point
absolutely Christine thank you very much
appreciate the
expertise okay okay okay uh the clock is
ticking to get your eclipse glasses and
make your Monday afternoon plans because
as you probably already know unless
you're living under a rock a total solar
eclipse is coming to America it's a Once
in a generation or maybe even once in a
lifetime event when the moon fall fully
blocks the Sun's light creating complete
darkness for a few minutes the path of
totality here it is right there running
through more than a dozen states turning
them into huge tourist attractions let
bring in NBC's Priscilla Thompson in one
of those areas just Southside of Dallas
Texas she's left the bar that she was in
an hour ago now she's out on the street
um hey perscilla Dallas is just one of
the first US cities right that will be
in the zone so how are they preparing
yeah Tom we're out on the streets with
the people these downtown streets in
Great Vine were bustling earlier today
their folks already starting to trickle
in and those numbers are going to
continue to grow on Saturday and Sunday
as Texas is expecting more than 1
million visitors to see this beautiful
eclipse and I spoke with Elizabeth with
the Chamber of Commerce here about how
this town is preparing and and what this
means what the impact could be I want to
play some of what she
shared how big of a bone do you think
this will be for businesses here yeah
we're going to have thousands of people
from all over the world all over the
country here and so everyone's really
excited they're all excited to see the
eclipse but also to have all these
visitors here shopping eating at the
amazing restaurants having lots of
fun and there are 83 counties in Texas
in the path of totality you can imagine
how many visitors they're going uh to be
seeing we've seen already that rentals
along that whole path of totality from
Texas to Maine are nearly completely
sold out so certainly a big economic
boom for small towns like this one and
larger ones like Dallas Tom yeah this
path of totality sounds so ominous
doesn't it but listen even if you aren't
in that path of totality uh people
across the country can still get a
glimpse of it maybe not a full exposure
but they can get a glimpse right so what
should they keep in
mind yeah some folks in New York City
will even be able to see a little bit of
it and the big thing to know is that if
you were staring up at the sun you've
got to make sure you've got your glasses
and you want to make sure that they have
that indicator on there that they are
certified glasses the real deal you can
pick them up at places like Target
Walmart even some local libraries and
certainly if you're going to an eclipse
event they will likely have them there
as well Tom hey Priscilla really quickly
uh zoom in to that little logo that we
need to see on the glasses so people can
know what should they be looking for
let's see that have your photographer
move in a little bit a little bit a
little bit okay that's what you should
be looking for to make sure that your
glasses are legit cuz last time we had a
lot of fraudulent glasses out there got
it all right want to be aware of that
absolutely thank you very much Priscilla
on the ground in Dallas coming up the
new trend at airports kind of freaking
out the TSA that's in the five things
and LeBron james' son wants his own shot
at the NBA why he is declaring for the
draft after his rough freshman year
we're coming back
[Music]
let's get you over now to the five
things our team thinks you should know
about tonight number one a woman
convicted of killing and poisoning her
friend with eye drops has been sentenced
to life in prison prosecutor said she
was the caregiver for the woman she
killed and was motivated by greed during
her sentencing earlier she said
investigators got it wrong number two a
federal appeals court says that the
justice department can reopen its
investig ation into the National
Association of Realtors Pro policies it
comes years after the group settled
government antitrust claims the group
tells Reuters today that the government
should be held to the terms of its
contracts remember last month they
agreed to a huge settlement in a big
Anti-Trust lawsuit on behalf of Home
sellers number three the TSA tells the
Washington Post hundreds of people have
bypassed airport security measures in
the past 12 months they're doing things
like sneaking through ID checkpoints and
going the wrong direction through oneway
exit Lanes a TSA spokesperson says most
of these rare bypasses are inadvertent
and unintentional uh actions by the
passengers they don't mean any harm
number four 99 Cents Only stores are
shutting down all 371 locations
nationwide the CEO says it's because of
factors like the pandemic and shifting
consumer demand and that it was an
extremely difficult decision decision
the shame will liquidate all of its
merchandise number five USC freshman
Bonnie James LeBron James's son will
enter the two make that the 2024 NBA
draft as well as the college transfer
portal now remember over the summer
bronny suffered a cardiac arrest while
at a basketball workout he had to have a
heart procedure and that Sid lined him
for several months coming up from us a
deadly truck crash in Bolivia what we're
learning now about the driver he may
have fallen asleep at the wheel and
college athletes are navigating
confusing new rules about how they can
get paid the one school trying to make
that a lot easier stay with
[Music]
us NBC News covers hundreds of
international stories every day and
because it's tough to read watch or
listen to them all our teams around the
world have done it for both you and from
me here's a look at what they're
watching we called the segment the
global we start in Bolivia at least 14
people are dead two others injured after
a crash involving a bus and a Truck
carrying salt local police arrested the
truck driver one of the only survivors
they think he may have fallen asleep at
the wheel in Russia Emergency Services
say a dam burst and the Euro mountains
forced a big evacuation something like
4,000 homes could be inundated the area
is dealing with just a ton of flooding
caused by melting snow from the nearby
mountains and in the UK the Guinness
Book of World Records says this 111 year
old man is the oldest living man his
name is John tenniswood he was born in
1912 before the first world war he says
his long life is quote just luck
tenniswood earn the title after the
previous record holder a 114-year-old
man in Venezuela died earlier this week
now to new reporting from NBC News
digital docks our team has been talking
about and talking to one mother's fight
to bring her son back home after he was
taken hostage by Hamas back on October
7th this is 23-year-old HS Goldberg
Poland in the nearly six months since
her son was taken Rachel Goldberg Poland
has become a vocal advocate in the
effort to free the more than 100
hostages still being held by Hamas all
while trying to pretend everything is
normal today is day 27 her she's still
not home 52 75 86 today is day 100 since
my son was stolen from me it's sad to be
known for something really painful and
really scary and that's what people
think of when they see
me every time we spoke to anyone in the
media they would say how many days has
it been so I just took masking tape and
started to make these
numbers and it makes people really ask
how are we allowing this to continue to
[Music]
happen the hostage families have to
pretend to be normal if we want to
function and if we want to save
[Music]
them first thing in the morning I always
say to myself and now pretend to be
human and I get out of bed and I put on
this costume of being a person I have a
walk that I do now in the mornings that
I've
crafted so that I don't see anybody and
I walk with my head down and I always
wear sunglasses I often have a hood if I
see people in the distance I cross to
the other side of the
street and all day long it's kind of of
like someone's holding a branding iron
on your back and you can't let anybody
[Music]
know I was asked early on if I would
speak at the United Nations in New York
and so I did why is no one crying out
for these people to be allowed access to
the Red Cross why is no one demanding
just proof of life we felt that the
advocacy for the hostage situation was
so important that we really never wanted
to say
[Applause]
[Music]
no I've had
episodes where I do break it's better
when I know that it's coming and I can
you know say I'll be right back and you
know go to my room or go to the bathroom
or go somewhere where it's not so public
but that's not the way trauma works
so there are definitely times where I'm
out there screaming or crying or laying
on the
street I'm also
extremely
heartbroken over the unbelievable
suffering of hundreds of thousands of
innocent and go and people what they are
going through it's unbearable and so
painful to
watch right now there are hundreds of
thousands of people suffering in this on
both sides and it's time for the
suffering to
stop on Shabbat morning I sit
down cross-legged right in front of this
big poster that we have of him that is
behind our front door I look into his
eyes and I talk to him and I tell him
you have to stay strong mentally
spiritually psychologically physically
religiously you have to survive you have
no choice we are coming you can make it
through this and you're going to have a
long beautiful life
one mother we'll be right
back back now to an NBC News exclusive
with the son of recording artist Shan Dy
Colmes also now accused of sexual
assault the new lawsuit first obtained
by NBC News accuses 26-year-old
Christian Colmes of sexually assaulting
a woman in December of 22 she says she
thought she was being hired for a
wholesome family Excursion on a yacht
that did charted instead she found a
quote hedonistic environment Diddy is
named in the lawsuit as well accused of
aiding and abetting his son in the last
couple of hours we've heard from a
lawyer for Diddy and his son calling
this a lewd and meritless claim from the
accuser's lawyer saying father and son
will file a motion to dismiss the
lawsuit now remember this moment from
those dramatic police raids earlier this
month at Diddy's home in Los Angeles and
also Miami Diddy has denied all
allegations related to the wave of
sexual assault and sex trafficking
allegations that he faces Chloe Mass
joins me now Chloe what else can you
tell us about this lawsuit against
Christian and Diddy Colmes and did this
come as a surprise nice to see you I
mean this woman is accusing Christian
Colmes of an incident that allegedly
took place in December 2022 just days
before Diddy had a really big party on
this yacht uh for New Year's Eve and the
victim claims that she was drugged and
sexually assaulted by Christian Colmes
again Christian Colmes is lawyer denying
these allegations uh she claims that
there are also audio recordings that
were taken by a music producer um who
was on The Yacht who was always
recording uh things that were going on
and just happened to catch some of the
exchanges between Christian Colmes and
this alleged victim that they believe
backs up her claims um NBC News has not
been able to independ independently
verify that and in the lawsuit there are
also uh photos of alleged bruises that
she says are because Christian Colmes
grabbed her now all of this um you know
was taking place allegedly in December
of 2022 and she claims that she was in a
room and somebody came in saw that this
was a bad situation and that that kept
her from being assaulted further and she
was able to get out and now she is
seeking specified Financial damages um
and again we've seen that uh you know
sha Diddy Colmes and his son are both
saying that they are going to fight this
and Diddy is included in all of this
because he was the one that procured the
yacht yeah so walk us through again the
allegations against Diddy and where the
investigation stands right now so I want
to just go through this timeline that we
have so this all kicked off in November
of 20123 when uh one of uh Diddy's
ex-girlfriends Cassie uh but her name is
Andra Ventura well-known singer and two
others sued Diddy for sexual abuse
something that he denied now uh you know
sha Diddy comes he settled that lawsuit
with Cassie like just about a day or so
later for an undisclosed amount of money
then December a woman comes forward uh
you we don't know her identity but
claims that she was raped by Diddy when
she was 17 years old um and then another
lawsuit February 2024 from a former
record producer who worked with Diddy on
his love album um accusing him of all
sorts of things including assault and
then like you showed that footage that
unbelievable footage of Diddy's homes
multiple properties being raided by
federal authorities last week and he
Diddy has not been charged with anything
criminally we do not know what those
Federal investigators found and if
they're ever going to reveal if anything
was found um and then obviously this
lawsuit that NBC News has exclusively
obtained and so you know things are not
looking good and um it'll be interesting
to see what happens over the course of
the coming weeks okay Khloe Moss
breaking the news thank you very much
Chloe coming up from Moss ticket prices
for tonight's women's final four through
the roof the ncaa's President says there
is no peak to the sports success what
about ticket prices we're coming
[Music]
back okay so we are just hours away now
from the most anticipated women's final
four ever with four four huge story
lines about to play out in Cleveland
tonight there's the bracket the opening
game with South Carolina the huge
favorites against an upstart North
Carolina State then the night cap a a
heavyweight bout with yukon's Paige
Beckers and the Superstar of this sport
right now you know who she is Iowa's
Caitlyn Clark audience experts expect
more than more records I should say
after 12 million people tuned in for
Monday's LSU Iowa game with the athletic
predicting anywhere from 8 million
viewers to nearly 17 million for the
final if it's Iowa against South
Carolina NBC Sam Brock will explain how
all of this turns into dollars for the
athletes in just a moment but let's
start though with NBC's Jesse kers in
Cleveland uh just outside the site of
this year's women's final four Bo you
got a rough assignment buddy you get you
get to watch the final four but this is
not just I I have a press pass that I
think would be worth a pretty penny but
of course ethics preclude me from uh
indulging in that we're going to go in
there in a little bit and check out
these games uh you just set the stage
we're looking at some Powerhouse
matchups and and the the finale to what
has been a historic tournament for the
women's game the NCAA says that each of
the rounds in this Championship leading
up to this weekend have broken
attendance records and you just talked
about Monday night LSU Iowa it was a
rematch from the the uh the championship
game last year and there were more
people watching that game than the
championship last year just gives you an
idea of the energy around these games
and like I just mentioned it's not cheap
to get in here take a look at some of
these ticket prices according to tickp
this is the highest we've ever seen for
an average ticket price for the women's
final four and the prices are almost
double what they were last year just
gives you an idea of how much excitement
there is around this we caught up with
some NCAA officials earlier including
the vice president for women's
basketball here's part of what she
shared with us let's go
I think it's a combination of both uh
you know exposure through TV but it's
social media our players out there their
personalities are coming out um we have
great coaches that are faces of the game
as well the skill and athleticism on the
court is phenomenal these are great
players the basketball skill the the
power that they
have we're looking at a lot of star
power across this game but of course one
name continues to stick out Tom and
that's Caitlin Clark yeah Jesse I've got
offers already coming in right now for
your press pass texting me right now all
right buddy uh listen we should know the
women are playing in a typical 18,000
seat basketball arena right we're not
even talking about the men's final 4
playing in a 70,000 football stadium so
any talk about when we might approach
parody yeah so we we talked to the NCAA
about this earlier and remember thas
just a couple years ago that there was a
lot of attention on disparity between
the weight room facilities for example
at the 2021 tournament for the women
versus the men and the NCAA President
and Vice President we spoke with earlier
talking about investment they've made to
bring that parody to both the men's and
the women's tournament and they said
that even with tournaments planned out
ahead specifically San Antonio they're
looking at larger venues for the women
and of course they plan these things out
years in advance uh but the expectation
is that this game continues to grow for
the women here's part of what the
president of the NCAA shared with us
earlier I want to think about this as
something where there is no peak right
it's just going to keep going up and the
goal for all of us is to continue to
make the Investments to drive that but
at the same time to be able to make the
changes despite the fact that we have to
plan many years in advance to be able to
absorb and um and take advantage of
that and that's of course what we're
talking about in in person attendance
specifically but don't forget Tom as you
mentioned talking about more than 12
million people that tuned in on Monday
night for a quarterfinal ESPN says that
was the most watched women's college
basketball game ever thanks for watching
stay updated about breaking news and top
stories on the NBC News app or follow us
on social media